Mike Smith

ATLANTA, GA

Phone: 770.851.0497 | Email: mike@mikeqsmith.com

Website: www.mikeqsmith.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mikeqsmith

GitHub: https://github.com/mqsmith

Summary

A Full Stack Web Developer certified by the Georgia Institute of Technology and Harvard University. Experienced professional leader with a 10-year background in live event production and a life-long dedication to continuous learning. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among teammates for collaboration and strong attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | jQuery | Bootstrap | Firebase | Node.js | MySQL | java |

MongoDB | Express | Handelbars.js | ReactJS.

Applications: Microsoft Office Suite | Google Suite | Final Cut Pro | Photoshop | After Effects, Illustrator

| InDesign | Keynote | Pro Presenter | Pro Video Sync | Pro Video Player

Projects

Slap Bet

Deployed Project: www.mikeqsmith.com/slapbet Repo: https://github.com/mqsmith/slapBet

Technologies used: D3, Chart.js, Formspree, Firebase, ajax, Bootstrap, ¡Query

Bananas 2 Bananas

Deployed Project: http://banana2banana.herokuapp.com/Repo: https://github.com/mqsmith/banans2bananas

Technologies used: MySQL, NodeJS, HTML, MaterializeCSS, JavaScript, ¡Query Dependencies

include: sequelize, express, path, doteny, nodemon, mysql2

Experience

Full Stack Web Developer

May 2019 to Present

Workflow Network – worked on adding features to Share Social Web App. https://workflow.network/sharesocial/

Passion Productions 2015 to 2019

Technical Director

Led all production aspects, e.g., technology, gear, and team leadership, for the Cumberland location and enterprise events including implementing the vision and culture of

Passion City Church within the production team. Ensured internal and external client satisfaction by building relationships, gaining trust and requesting feedback.

- Launched a new location and set the ground work for future teams to step into
- Cultivated a consistent rotation of volunteers through leadership and motivation, solving a years-long issue for the company
- Managed a yearly budget of \$900,000

Technical Coordinator

Led multiple teams of production contractors to execute events with audio, lighting, video and performances by managing pre-planning calls, gear rental, and other event preparation.

Freelance Live Event Production

2009 to 2015

Production Technician

Served as Producer, Programming Director, Lighting Director and Lighting Designer. Scheduled and trained volunteer teams on proper implementation and storage of production equipment. Managed and archived all production data.

AE Production Services

2011 to 2012

Production Technician

Served as Lighting Designer, Audio Director, Stage Manager, Inventory and Gear Specialist, and Technician for various music festivals with artists including: Dierks Bentley, Edwin McCain, Daughtry, Luke Bryan, Atlanta Party Band, David Nail, and Parmalee.

Education

Full Stack Web Developer Certificate: Georgia Institute of Technology Introductory Computer Science Certificate: HarvardX of Harvard University

Bachelor of Arts, Sports Business: University of Georgia

Completed 100/120 hours